The story of America's most dangerous drug trafficker.
American Sicario is a crime, action film directed by Raja Collins.
The story of the rise and fall of the first American-born drug lord in Mexico, this tale of power, money, greed and betrayal amongst rival members of the drug cartels finds American
gangster Erik Vasquez scheming to become the top dog in the Mexican underworld, only to find himself making enemies out of both the powerful cartels and his own allies.
Erik Vasquez, played by Philippe A. Haddad.
Pedro, played by Danny Trejo.
Gloria, played by Cali Morales.
Roberto, played by Maurice Compte.
Dominic, played by Jaylen Moore.
Juan Feliz, played by Johnny Rey Diaz.
Sicario is a 2015 American action crime thriller film directed by Denis Villeneuve, written by Taylor
Sheridan in his screenwriting debut and starring Emily Blunt, Benicio del Toro, and Josh Brolin.
The film follows a principled FBI special agent who is enlisted by a government task
force to bring down the leader of a powerful and brutal Mexican drug cartel.
Sicario was selected to compete for the Palme d'Or
at the 2015 Cannes Film Festival.
It began a limited release in the United States on September 18, 2015,
followed by a nationwide release on October 2, 2015.
Sicario received praise for its cast performances, writing,
direction, musical score and cinematography.
The film was nominated for Best Cinematography, Best Original Score,
and Best Sound Editing at the 88th Academy Awards.
It also earned BAFTA nominations for Best Supporting Actor,
Best Cinematography, and Best Film Music.
Its sequel, Sicario: Day of the Soldado, directed by
Stefano Sollima, was released on June 29, 2018.
A third film, titled Sicario: Capos, is in development.
The film is the first installment of writer Taylor Sheridan's American
Frontier Trilogy, proceeding Hell or High Water and Wind River.